#### **FABIAN M. KETIKU**

Email:ksope2002@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/sope-ketiku Github: https://github.com/ksope

#### **PROFILE:**

I'm very passionate about IT and currently on the path to being a Full Stack Web Developer with a previous record in software quality assurance and building architecture. My strong technical knowledge and outstanding interpersonal skills enable me to interact with a wide range of clients. I also have several years of work experience leading teams across different sectors. I'm eager to learn, grow and improve my skills.

#### **SKILLS**

- Frontend Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React
- Backend Development: Node.js, Express, MongoDB
- Development Testing: (Jest, Cucumber, Puppeteer) Unit Testing, Integration Testing, UAT and Endto-End testing
- Excellent Problem Solving skills
- Analyse complex scenarios
- Effective communication and collaboration with team members
- Keen attention to detail
- Resilient. Always seeking ways to improve how things are done.

# **Qualifications:**

ISTQB/ISEB Certification (2006).

# **EDUCATION**

2005 – 2007	M.Sc Computer Science School of Computing, Science and Engineering University of Salford, Greater Manchester, United Kingdom
1999 – 2001	MSc Architecture University of Lagos, Lagos, Nigeria
1995 – 1999	B.Sc (Hons) Architecture University of Lagos, Lagos, Nigeria

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Nov 2008 - Jun 2020

Collaborations Integrated Systems Limited, Lagos, Nigeria

# **Director/Business Development/ Quality Assurance**

I was a co-founder of an elearning start-up that developed a Learning Management System which was successfully deployed after meeting the expectations of the bank's rigorous internal audit checks for security, performance, reliance and accountability to serve over 3000 staff for one of the major banks in Nigeria.

I helped establish an exclusive partnership in Nigeria for Intuition, U.K, which has a library of the world's largest catalogue of globally relevant financial market e-learning.

### Aug 2011 - Jun 2022

BrundtLand Projects Limited, Lagos, Nigeria

# Lead Design Architect/ Head, Implementation Team

I started a design and build company which comprised a technical team of 8 people.

I successfully helped clients outline their briefs and ensured implementation within project timelines while helping clients stay within their budgets in a very dynamic cost environment without compromising quality standards.

### Nov 2007-Sept 2008

Result Group Ltd, Elland, West Yorkshire

# **Software Test Analyst**

I participated in preparing test scenarios for use in the UAT test phase. I studied design specifications, functional specifications and supporting documentation created by development / business users and created test scripts and test cases.

I was involved in the manual running of test script and logging defects into the problem report form.

I used a QTP automation tool for run and capture tasks

### 2005-2006

Apache OpenOffice.org

#### **Volunteer Software Test User**

I was also a member of the QA team, testing an open source software called Open Office suite, version 2.3 where I was reporting defects and also involved in manual testing.

# 2004-2005

Tara Systems Limited Network and Internet Service Provider (<a href="https://www.metrong.com">www.metrong.com</a>).

Lagos, Nigeria

# **Network Systems Analyst**

I worked at an Internet Service Provider to develop my interest in I.T. I served as a Technical Support Engineer to all MetronNG high speed Internet customers and staff.

I was involved in online and telephone technical support for all clients. I assisted in the installation of outdoor fixed wireless, fiber, infrared and DSL solutions thereby providing dedicated bandwidth for corporate clients which included the BBC, Haliburton and the Austrian Embassy.